Aaron Bolger

37 Barrymore Avenue, Cobh, Cork.
DOB: 24/07/90
bolgeraaron@gmail.com
0866610714
ie.linkedin.com/in/aaronbolgermsc

Projects

MSc Interactive Media Final Project

Completed between July 2014 - October 2014 in User input and navigation for Virtual Reality Head-Mounted Displays. Proposed by Logitech in Cork. The project utilised the Oculus Rift HMD and Leap motion controller. Technologies included Unreal Engine 4 with Blueprint scripting, Blender, and minimal work in C++. Research focus was natural user interfacing and experience, and included design and programming of natural Leap gestures.

Extended Virtual Reality Project presented to Logitech

Continuing from my MSc. project. Additional programmed gestures and enhanced navigation was added. The project was then presented to Logitech, who presented it at their worldwide consortium in Switzerland.

Quiz for Children affected by PCD

Independent work creating and repairing a Flash-based quiz. Involved programming AS3 in Flash, HTML, and XML. Also involved decompiling SWF files as no access to source was available. Completed for the University of Southampton.

Information site and Monitoring tool for Molar Pregnancy

Work in progress - Project for an obstetrics specialist in CUH for monitoring blood tests and receiving visual feedback through a web interface. Tool uses a combination of HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, AJAX and MySql, and may use Python for a single input system.

Education

Sept 2012 - Oct 2014

MSc. Interactive Media,

University College Cork.

Completed project in Alternative User Input and Navigation for Virtual Reality Head-Mounted Displays

Complete in 2014 - 1:1 Awarded for Project, 2:1 Awarded overall.

Sept 2008 - June 2012

B.A. Honours Degree (Level 8) in Visual Art,

Waterford Institute of Technology.

Completed project in the Experience of Art through audio and technical installations. Completed in 2012.

Work Experience

Feb 2014 - Present

Website Developer/Administrator

VetsFirst Group Ltd., 3a, Eastlink Business Park, Carrigtwohill, Cork. Designing front-end, developing server-side, and maintaining web sites for each veterinary clinic managed by VetsFirst. Building and maintaining a Content Management System specifically for these sites, and the main site for VetsFirst. Technologies include HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, MySQL. Other duties include photography/photo editing (Photoshop), video editing (Premiere), and interfacing with clinics for feedback, changes etc.

Sites can all be viewed from: http://www.vetsfirstgroup.ie/

Sept 2014 - Present

In-Class Tutor/Demonstrator

University College Cork, Western Gateway Building, Western Road, Cork. Providing assistance and tutoring for current MSc. Interactive Media students in X3D, Three.js, Processing(Java), Digital Video, 3D Modelling and Animation. I also provide grinds for students who request it.

Jan 2015 - Present

MPT Kiddo Tutor

University College Cork, Western Gateway Building, Western Road, Cork. In-class assistance and demonstration for the Kiddo branch of Munster Programming Training on Saturday mornings. Tutoring and helping 6th class kids learn how to code through such technology as Scratch, Kudo and Python.

Nov - Dec 2013

Coderdojo Mentor

Cobh, Co. Cork.

Volunteer mentor and teaching position with the Cobh branch of Coderdojo. I taught the Processing language to students between 12-18 on Saturday mornings in St. Mary's Primary school.

Mar 2012 - Sept 2014

Customer Service Agent, Work from Home

Amazon.co.uk, Airport Business Park, Airport Road Cork. Supporting customers through phone, email and chat services, aiding in everyday order issues, account issues, etc.

Sept 2008 - Oct 2011

Technical Support Agent/Technician

TalkTalk UK, IDA Industrial Estate, Cork Road, Waterford.
Assisting customers and field technicians in technical broadband, TV and PC issues via phone. Also managing customers phone line and broadband in back-office tools. Involved broad knowledge of local and internet networking, hardware and general IT skills.

Technologies

Languages

- JavaScript
- PHP
- HTML5/CSS3
- X3E
- Python 2.7/3.4
- Processing
- ActionScript 3
- Objective-C (X-Code)
- XML
- C++

Related Technologies

- MySQL
- AJAX
- Three.js
- Recommender Systems
- PhoneGap
- Bootstrap

3D, Graphics, Video, Audio

- Adobe Creative Suite
- > Photoshop
- > Premiere Pro
- > After Effects
- > Illustrator
- Unreal Engine 4
- Blender
- Maya
- Final Cut Pro
- Ableton Live
- Audacity
- Logic X

ProTools

Operating Systems

- Windows, 2000 -> 8.1
- Mac OSX Lion+
- Linux -> Ubuntu
- Android 2+
- iOS 4+
- Windows Phone 7+

Skills

- Creative Problem Solving
- Extremely Visual person with strong aesthetic knowledge
- Strong Human-Computer Interaction/Interfacing knowledge
- Good working knowledge of networking and the web
- Solid People Skills
- Very reliable and solid team worker

Interests

I am very interested in and try to keep up to date with emerging technology, getting involved in small coding and gaming side-projects with friends, and keeping myself up to scratch by doing programming challenges online. I am an avid gamer, mainly on PC. Also interested in all aspects of creating games, from coding through to design. Occasionally produce electronic music and host it online using Soundcloud; also very into art and design, holding a BA. I'm a former scout, in 15th Waterford troop 6 years and Waterford City Venturers for 2, and as such I enjoy hiking, camping and generally exploring.

References

Mr David Murphy;

Senior Lecturer, Dept. Computer Science, University College Cork <u>d.murphy@cs.ucc.ie</u>

Dr Sabin Tabirca;

Senior Lecturer, Dept. Computer Science, University College Cork <u>tabirca@cs.ucc.ie</u>; 087-2772036

Mr Kevin McNamara;

Managing Directoy, VetsFirst Ltd kevin@vba.ie; 0871273281

Mr Paul John Quilty;

Technical Support Team Manager, TalkTalk UK. 085-1944939